Hello friends, my name is Sachin and
today I have brought another video for you.
So friends, today we are going to start the
accidental insurance series. Till now
we were reviewing health insurance
and we will continue doing that. Along with this,
we will discuss
about accidental insurance. What is cadet term
insurance, how does it work
and what are its benefits. Right now we will
just introduce you today. I will
go through some of its basic concepts. It is
important to understand this so that when we
review the product in the future
because there are its technical aspects ahead. It will be
very easy for you to understand it. You will understand it easily. So
friends, let us understand
what are the basic concepts of
accidental insurance. So first of all, it is
important for us to know what is an accident.
If I
talk about the definition of accident, then it
says that and unfortunately incident that happens
unexpectedly and intentional
tips
resulting in times and injury means that
such an incident that happened suddenly, okay, which is
completely unexpected.  It was something which you had
no idea that such a thing would happen to you
and even if it was unintentional, that is, it was
not done intentionally, due to which you suffered
damage, loss or injury,
this is called an accident. As
you all know, if you are walking on the road
and a vehicle hits you from behind,
that is an accident. If you are driving
and you get hurt by it,
that is also an accident.
If you fall from the roof, that is also an accident. If
you fall in the bathroom and
you get hurt, that is also an accident. So
friends, even a snake bite is an accident. There
can be many such things which have happened unfortunately, very
unexpectedly, and which have caused you
harm. So all those things
come under the category of accident.
Hello friends, today we are inspecting
dental insurance coverage,
so let us know
how many types of accidental insurance are there. So
friends, it is done in two ways, I will
list which we  It is called Individual
Personal Accidental Insurance which is
called IPL in short and there is another one called
Group Personal Accidental Insurance which
we call GPF so friends individual means
any person who takes this policy
without taking it in a group then he
is an individual and in group means where
a company is taking a single policy for 10, 20, 500 of its employees
then we
call it group insurance the work of both is almost
similar so here what we are going to
discuss will be
about Individual Personal Accidental and
we will discuss about group at some other end
so friends let us understand
what are the
meter sections in an accidental insurance if you understand this then
whenever you will see the
insurance accidental insurance of any company then
you will easily understand
what are the benefits in it and
how will it work so I am
telling you these major sectors apart from this there are some
actions also which will gradually cover in
their coming years  Inside the product review videos,
you will understand all the things there, so
friends, first of all there
is Accidental Death Benefit, second is
Permanent Total Disability, third point is
different shoes called Pvt, in short,
similarly Temporary Total Disability TTD
and a hospital, see if you have an accident, then
this is the main
important one, so let us
discuss it one by one so that you will understand in more detail, so first of all there is
Accidental Death Benefit, friends,
if suppose
you die in an accident, then whatever you have taken, that is,
suppose if you have
taken this plan of Rs 50 lakh, then it is possible
that if you die, then the
entire ₹5000000 will be deposited in your bank
account, friends,
before moving forward, let me tell you that
if you are new to my channel, then please do
not forget to subscribe and
also press the bell icon and if you like this video of mine  If you
like it then do not forget to share it
because knowledge increases by sharing, so
friends, we consider it permanent,
look at that diplomat, the
thing about permanent placement is that you have got into such a
situation that you are
not even capable of working, then in this case
you are given the entire money
together so that you can live your life or
else you are
given this money in monthly report i.e. in minister mode so that you can meet the
expenses of your family, so let us
understand it a little in detail and the
first one is fennel, so lips means that when
here both your hands are cut or
both your legs are cut or you have one hand and one
leg, then you will be given the
entire money forever and whatever amount you had paid, in the
same way lots of gloom and eye,
if your hand is cut and you lose your eye, then
you will get 100% money,
if you lose the complete irrecoverable
sight of both eyes,
here also you will get this 100%
money, Sameshwar  You will get it. Similarly,
if you lose your power to speak or hear,
then also you will get
hundred percent sum insured here. Similarly,
if one of your hands gets cut, then
you will get 50% sum insured
money here. Similarly, if we
talk completely, that is,
if one of your eyes loses its sight, then
you will get 50% of its money here.
Time is left for
friends, let's move ahead. Here we
talk about permanent
placement like a parcel disability, that is,
something due to which you have
not suffered complete loss, but
some part of your body has been cut or
damaged, then for that also the
company gives you some percentage of money.
So let's discuss this friends, now
if any inch of your arm and shoulder
joint, if any
joint of yours except the arm gets injured, then you will get 70% of the
money. Similarly, if the injury
to the point value joint, that is, your elbow
joint,  If the injury goes from bottom to top, then
you will get sixty five percent
of the money, leaving the same amount. Similarly, in
common bills, if your elbow joint, that is,
whichever is below, then only
fifty percent of the money is given to you. If
your hand gets cut till the wrist, then fifty percent of the money is given to you, that is, the
thumb of
your hand is lost, then twenty percent of the money is given to you.
If you lose one eye, then 50% of the money is given to you. Hearing loss
of each ear, any meaning of one ear
's hearing ability is also lost, then
30% of that is given to the middle leg, that is, if one of your
legs is lost from the center of the body till the heart, then
here
you get up to 70% of the money, leaving the same amount. So
friends, now you are understanding that even
if your body is not completely damaged, even if
you mean if death has
not occurred, then also this plan
works for you. So friends, my advice is
that you must keep this type of policy
in your portfolio. In this way,
if we talk further about temperature
retardation, all this
Bluetooth settings are called closed kidney,
so friends, what happens here is that suppose you have a
fracture in an accident and the
doctor has asked you for a transplant,
okay, so if you have been asked to
rest for two months, then
what will happen here, you get the parcel sum
insured money, it is approximately one
percent, suppose you had
taken a plan of 50 lakhs, then weekly you will get one
percent money i.e. ₹5000 per week, as long as
you are on bed, suppose the doctor has told you two
months' bed rest, then for
8 weeks you will keep getting ₹5000
and this can go up to a maximum of that week, so
here the
doctor will
certify the temporary displacement, that is, he will make a decorated certificate, then
you will be able to get this money,
similarly friends, if we
talk about hospitalization benefit, suppose
you get some such injury
where your treatment is done in the hospital
or suppose you can get stitches
So what happens there is that
if you have taken this hospital cover
or it is inbuilt in some policies,
which we
will discuss in the coming time, so if you have this option in
it, then you will also get some hospital treatment
expenses, generally it is of Rs 1 lakh to 2 lakh,
so if you have
taken an option in it, then you will get this money in
any mode, cashless or reimbursement,
but the hospitalization there should be more than
24 hours, so I
hope friends, you have understood the basic concept
of accidental insurance and
if you have understood it, then do
not forget to share this video, see you
friends in the next video,
thank you very much for watching this video